Shreyas Vedpathak

04 Jan 2001 | shreyasvedpathak@gmail.com | 9881898291 | Pune, India | LinkedIn ID: shreyasvedpathak Github ID: shreyasvedpathak | Website: shreyasvedpathak.github.io | Stackoverflow ID: shreyasvedpathak

PROFILE

A software engineering graduate with 1.5+ years of experience in software development in the domains of computer vision, backend development, and research & development. I am seeking to utilize my broad educational background with excellent analytical, technical, and programming skills to thrive as an entry-level software engineer.

EDUCATION

2018 – 2022 Pune, India	MIT World Peace University, Bachelor of Technology ☐ Branch: Computer Science and Technology CGPA: 9.52
2016 – 2018 Pune, India	Sir Parashurambhau College, HSC Domain: Science Percentage: 81%

SKILLS

Python • C++ • MySQL • MongoDB • Scikit Learn • PyTorch • Tensorflow • HTML • CSS • JavaScript jQuery • Flask • OpenCV • Docker • Node.js

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nov 2021 – present Ahmedabad, India

Computer Vision Intern, *Upjao Agrotech* ☑

- Worked on novel problems related to the Agro-industry with Deep Learning as well as traditional computer vision methods with OpenCV.
- Created a modular Python package that would generate a numerical report. Helped decrease server response time by 45 percent.
- Contributed to the Patent team's research, brainstorming, and implementation of the patent idea for production servers.
- Restructured the server architect to make it scalable and flexible with Docker and Kubernetes.

Aug 2021 – present Palo Alto, USA

Mentor, *DeepLearning.AI* □

- Helped candidates enrolled in specific Coursera courses by solving their doubts, sharing learning material, and career advice.
- Test new lab exercises before they are released to enrolled students.

Mar 2021 – Jun 2021 Pune, India

Data Analyst Intern, *Analytics Domain* ♂

- Created a web application-based analysis tool that would leverage data from public APIs and web scraping.
- Curated 2 courses for Machine Learning and Deep Learning topics at the beginner and intermediate levels.
- With the produced courses and a variety of user-side UI features, developed a web app-based Learning Management System.

PUBLICATIONS

Jun 2021 Genomics, High Performance Computing and Machine Learning,

UIJRT (United International Journal for Research & Technology) ♂

This paper aims to explore in a very uncomplicated manner, what exactly is genomics, where does high performance computing and machine learning come into picture, current applications and discuss potential future scope.

Nov 2020

PCOcare PCOS Detection and Prediction using Machine Learning Algorithms,

Bioscience Biotechnology Research Communications ☑

Using 5 Machine Learning Algorithms, this research attempts to provide a system that can aid in the early diagnosis and prediction of PCOS therapy based on an optimal and minimal set of parameters.

PATENTS

Jan 2022 Ahmedabad, India

A method and system for Encoding and Decoding data on objects by using geometrical shaped markers., *Patent Pending*

A strong alternative to QR codes, barcodes, and RFIDs for simultaneously tagging, tracking, and recognizing multiple objects using computer vision techniques.

AWARDS

Nov 2020

Best Paper Award,

International Conference on Intelligent Systems, Data Science and Computing □ Best Research Paper Award in Machine Learning Track.

PROJECTS

Nov 2021 – present

AutiScan, Final Year Project

To collect data on autism-affected Indian children and determine whether or not they have ASD. The candidate's reaction to a reference video is recorded, and their facial landmarks are utilized to classify them using a CNN + RNN deep learning model.

May 2021 - Sep 2021

Segmentation of Fire and Smoke in Nano-Satellite Imagery using Mask R-CNN and Res-UNet, Research Project

Image Segmentation Algorithms like Mask R-CNN, UNet, and Deep Residual U-NET were successfully applied and separated natural objects such as clouds, snow, and rivers against smoke caused by a forest fire.

Jun 2021 – Jul 2021

Loan Management System - Flask API, Private Project

Simple loan management API made with FLASK as the backend and SQLite as the database. Token-based authentication, with Flask Blueprints for future scaling.

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

PCOcare: PCOS Detection & Prediction using ML, Research Project ☑

A system that can aid in the early identification and prediction of PCOS treatment is offered. There were several Machine Learning classifiers used. For feature engineering, the CHI square strategy is employed.

CERTIFICATES

• DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer • TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques ☑

• Generative Adversarial Networks (GANS) ☑